1

Applied Computer Science Research Group Fachbereich Informatik

University of Hamburg Vogt-Koelln-Strasse, 30 Hamburg, 22527 Germany Phone: +49 163 400 6714 fucci@informatik.uni-hamburg.de http://dfucci.ink

DAVIDE FUCCI

Citizenship

Italian

Research Interests Empirical software engineering, Agile software development and testing, affective computing and psycho-physiology for software and requirements engineering. I have a strong interest in methodological aspects and empirical approaches, as well as open science.

Education

University of Oulu, Oulu, Finland

2013-2016

Ph.D. in Software Engineering with honors, May 2016 Advisors: Prof. Burak Turhan & Prof. Markku Oivo

University of Oulu, Oulu, Finland

2010-2012

Master degree in Computer Sciencegrade 4/5, September 2012

University of Bari, Bari, Italy

2009-2010

Master degree in Computer Science

University of Bari, Bari, Italy

2004-2008

Bachelor degree in Computer Sciencegrade 96/100, December 2008

Employment

HITeC e.V. & University of Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany

2/2017-

Post-doctoral Researcher

University of Oulu, Oulu, Finland

6/2016-12/2016

Post-doctoral Researcher

PaneMerkille Ay, Oulu, Finland

07/2012-12/2014

Founder & CTO

Founded a startup as a spin-off of university project.

Developed front-end and back-end using Javascript technologies.

Advanced Computer Systems, Trani, Italy

5/2007-08/2009

Software developer

Developed test infrastructure for legacy code.

Developerd in-house DHW solution using C# and .NET technologies.

Teaching Experience (Classroom) Instructor, Designer,

Spring 2018

CS4240: Large-Scale Parallel Data Processing

Northeastern

Instructor, Designer,

Fall 2016

CS7680: Programming Models for Distributed Computation

Northeastern

Co-Instructor, Co-Designer, (with Viktor Kunčak & Martin Odersky)

Spring 2016

CS 206: Parallelism & Concurrency

EPFL

Co-Instructor, Co-Designer, (with Viktor Kunčak & Martin Odersky)

Spring 2015

CS 212: Reactive Programming & Parallelism

EPFL

(Lead) Teaching Assistant,Fall 2011-2014CS 201: Functional ProgrammingEPFL

Publications: Journals

A Programming Model and Foundation for Lineage-Based Distributed JFP 2018 Computation (to appear)

Heather Miller, Philipp Haller, Normen Müller

Journal of Functional Programming

Special Issue: Programming Languages for Big Data

Publications: Conferences

Simplicitly: Foundations and Applications of Implicit Function Types

POPL 2018

Martin Odersky, Olivier Blanvillain, Fengyun Liu, Aggelos Biboudis

Heather Miller, Sandro Stucki

ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages

Function Passing: A Model for Typed, Distributed Functional **Programming**

SPLASH 2016

Heather Miller, Philipp Haller, Normen Müller, Joceyln Boullier ACM SIGPLAN International Symposium on New Ideas, New Paradigms, and Reflections on Programming & Software

Spores: A Type-Based Foundation for Closures in the Age of Concurrency and Distribution

ECOOP 2014

Heather Miller, Philipp Haller, Martin Odersky European Conference on Object Oriented Programming

Functional Programming For All! Scaling a MOOC for Students And Professionals Alike

ICSE 2014

Heather Miller, Philipp Haller, Lukas Rytz, Martin Odersky ACM SIGSOFT International Conference on Software Engineering

Instant Pickles: Generating Object-Oriented Pickler Combinators for Fast and Extensible Serialization

OOPSLA 2013

PLACES 2015

Heather Miller, Philipp Haller, Eugene Burmako, Martin Odersky ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Object Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages and Applications

Publications: Workshops

Distributed Programming via Safe Closure Passing

Philipp Haller, Heather Miller

Programming Language Approaches to Communication

and Concurrency Centric Systems

RAY: Integrating Rx and Async for Direct-Style Reactive Streams

Philipp Haller, Heather Miller

ACM SPLASH Workshop on Reactivity, Events and Modularity

FlowPools: A Lock-Free Deterministic Concurrent Dataflow Abstraction

LCPC 2012

REM 2013

Aleksandar Prokopec, Heather Miller, Tobias Schlatter,

Philipp Haller, Martin Odersky

International Workshop on Languages and Compilers for Parallel Computing

Invited to Revised Selected Papers on the 25th International Workshop on Languages and Compilers for Parallel Computing, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, Vol. 7760, 2013

Tools and Frameworks for Big Learning in Scala: Leveraging the Language for High Productivity and Performance

BigLearn 2011

Heather Miller, Philipp Haller, Martin Odersky

NIPS Workshop on Parallel and Large-Scale Machine Learning

Parallelizing Machine Learning – Functionally: A Framework and Abstractions for Parallel Graph Processing Philipp Haller, Heather Miller Scala Workshop	Scala 2011
The Function Passing Model: Types, Proofs, and Semantics Philipp Haller, Normen Müller, Heather Miller	May 2016
Specialising Parsers for Queries April 2016 Manohar Jonnalagedda, Jorge Vicente Cantero, Heather Miller, Martin Odersky	
Improving Human-Compiler Interaction Through Customizable Type Feedback Hubert Plociniczak, Heather Miller, Martin Odersky	December 2014
Self-Assembly: Lightweight Language Extension and Datatype Generic Programming, All-in-One! Heather Miller, Philipp Haller, Bruno C. d. S. Oliveira	August 2014
Spores, Formally Heather Miller, Philipp Haller	December 2013
FlowPools: A Lock-Free Deterministic Concurrent Dataflow Abstraction – Proofs Aleksandar Prokopec, Heather Miller, Philipp Haller	June 2012
Trends in Functional Programming in Education (TFPIE)	016, 2017, 2018 2018 013, 2014, 2017 C) 2016, 2017
Organizing Committee Member: Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages & Applications (OOPSLA) 2018 European Conference on Object-Oriented Programming (ECOOP) 2015 – 2018	
Program Committee Member: International Conference on Functional Programming (ICFP) Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages & Applications (OOPS) Off the Beaten Track (OBT) Scala Symposium (Scala) Symposium on Trends in Functional Programming (TFP) Software Language Engineering (SLE) Symposium on Applied Computing (SAC) Programming Language Evolution (PLE) Domain-Specific Language Design and Implementation (DSLDI)	2018 SLA) 2017 2018 2016 2016 2016 2016 2015 2015
External Review Committee Member: PLDI 2018, ECOOP 2016, ECOOP 2013, Scala 2013	

Artifact Evaluation Committee: POPL 2015

External

Service

Summer 2018

Northeastern

Girls Code It: Intensive Pre-College Computer Science Program Conceived of and am organizing large pre-college program aimed at

preparing high school-aged girls for a career in Computer Science.

6 week-long residential program for 100 students which awards college credit and puts alumni of the program on an accelerated CS track upon matriculating at Northeastern University.

ScalaBridge Organizer

Organizer of free full-day workshops on the weekends aimed at teaching women and underrepresented minorities in computing how to think computationally and how to program in Scala.

ScalaBridge Chapters: Basel (CH), Zürich (CH), Copenhagen (DK), Boston (US).

Honors

US National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship	2011 - 2014
EPFL Outstanding Teaching Award	2012
EPFL Computer Science Fellowship	2009 - 2010
Most Outstanding Audio Engineering Student, University of Miami	2009
Most Outstanding Eta Kappa Nu Student, University of Miami	2009
Information Technology Scholarship, University of Miami	2006 - 2009
John Farina Family Scholarship, University of Miami	2006 - 2009
Eta Kappa Nu	2008
Tau Beta Pi	2008
SMART US Department of Defense Scholarship Alternate	2007
Cooper Union Full Tuition Scholarship	2004 - 2006

Selected Talks

What Happened to Distributed Programming Languages?

Strange Loop & PWLConf 2017 (invited)

St. Louis, MO, USA. September 29, 2017

The Dramatic Consequences of the Open Source Revolution: Unrecognized Challenges & Some Modest Attempts at Devoxx 2017 (invited)

Solutions in Scala

Paris, France. April 7, 2017

The Dramatic Consequences of the Open Source Revolution & How the Scala Center Hopes to Help

Scala Exchange 2016 (keynote)

London, UK. December 9, 2016

Function Passing: A Model for Typed, Distributed Functional Programming

SPLASH 2016

Amsterdam, The Netherlands. November 2, 2016

Introducing the Scala Center

Scala Days 2016

New York, NY, US. May 10, 2016 & Berlin, Germany. June 16, 2016

(keynote)

(total ~1700 attendees)

Function Passing Style: Typed, Distributed Functional Programming

Strange Loop 2014

St. Louis, MO, USA. September 19, 2014

Spores: A Type-Based Foundation for Closures in the Age of

ECOOP 2014

Concurrency and Distribution Uppsala, Sweden. August 1, 2014

Functional Programming For All! Scaling a MOOC for

ICSE 2014

Students and Professionals Alike

Hyderabad, India. June 4, 2014

Academese to English: Scala's Type System, Dependent Types

NEScala 2014

and What It Means To You

New York, NY, USA. March 1, 2014

Instant Pickles: Generating Object-Oriented Pickler Combinators for Fast and Extensible Serialization OOPSLA 2013

Indianapolis, IN, USA. October 30, 2013

PL Abstractions for Distributed Programming: Pickle Your Spores!

Indiana University (invited)

Bloomington, IN, USA. October 25, 2013

Spores: Distributable Functions in Scala

Strange Loop 2013

St. Louis, MO, USA. September 19, 2013

Open Issues in Dataflow Programming

LaME 2013 (invited)

Montpellier, France. July 1, 2013

Scala as a Research Tool

ECOOP 2013 Tutorial

Montpellier, France. July 1, 2013

On Pickles & Spores: Improving Scala's Support for Distributed Programming

New York, NY, USA. June 12, 2013

ScalaDays 2013

2016 -

Futures & Promises in Scala 2.10

Philadelphia, PA, USA. April 2, 2013

PhillyETE 2013 (invited)

Students Supervised Kevin Clancy, Eventual Consistency via Types

PhD thesis Northeastern

Joceyln Boullier, Evaluating the Efficiacy of the Function Passing Model 2/2016 – 8/2016 M.Sc. thesis EPFL

Jorge Vicente Cantero, *Implementing the Function Passing Model* 2/2016 – 6/2016 B.Sc. thesis EPFL

Thaddée Yann Tyl, Learning Scala Style 2/2013 – 6/2013 M.Sc. thesis EPFL

References

Martin Odersky, Professor

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne

☎ +41 21 693 68 63 ⊠ martin.odersky@epfl.ch

Jan Vitek, Professor Northeastern University

2 +1-617-749-8148

⊠ j.vitek@northeastern.edu

Matei Zaharia, Assistant Professor

Matthias Felleisen, Trustee Professor

Stanford University

↑ +1-510-610-0001

Imatei@cs.stanford.edu

Northeastern University

⊠ matthias@ccs.neu.edu

2 +1-617-373-2085

Philipp Haller, Assistant Professor KTH Royal Institute of Technology

☎ +46 70 738 28 43 ⋈ phaller@kth.se